[Music]
il cafe we have you covered
a podcast on how technology drives
innovation in the insurance industry
good to have you join us on il cafe this
is icici lombard's podcast that is
dedicated to all things you guessed it
right insurance now on this series we're
going to be looking at some of those
thought-provoking ideas that are
revolutionizing the insurance space
today whether it's technologies like
artificial intelligence or ensure tech
or digitization and i need several other
innovations that are going to be shaping
the future of the sector but i'm sure
the question that all of us are asking
right now is what's in it for me the
average consumer how does all of this
alter my experience of buying insurance
well guess what we've got you covered
you the listener join us on every
episode as we explore these ideas with
some really dynamic thought leaders
innovators doers who are leading this
change across the industry now to kick
off the first and hence very special
episode of our podcast series that's
titled technology drives innovation in
the insurance industry we're pleased to
have with us icici lombard's very own
girish naik girish is of course the
chief of customer service technology and
operations at icici lombard welcome to
the shogirish happy to have you here on
the very first episode of vial cafe how
are you i'm good cheetah thank you for
having me here and
it's a pleasure to be on first episode
of uh ayal cafe the pleasure is all ours
girish in fact we're gonna be even more
pleased when you address some of our
questions for us on this podcast but you
know i like to begin with the basics so
let me ask you what are those current
trends we've all seen that the pandemic
effect has really uh cut across every
single sector but generally speaking
what is the landscape like in the indian
insurance industry garish thank you for
the question i'll i'll start with the
second part of the question first on the
landscape of the indian insurance
industry
so the insurance industry is a fast
growing industry we sell close to 250
million plus policies a year and we have
more to that close of premium that we
collect but after all that our
penetration is hardly about one percent
of gdp it's significantly lower than
even uh countries like brazil russia and
of course china and
it's not that the government has not
been doing efforts to promote insurance
they've got health insurance scheme for
the below poverty line piece and all
that but in spite of all these efforts
if you look at the coverage of health
insurance you have a 34 coverage life
insurance will be somewhere in the
region of 28 to 30
even for say like motor vehicle
insurance which is legally required we
have about 40 percent of two wheelers
covered so really there's a lot more
that can be really done for insurance
penetration the industry also
traditionally has been very physical in
nature i mean i mean i say physical it
means that we really thrive on physical
interactions on the policy purchase end
you have the brokers the agents the oem
dealers who are helping with the
sourcing of the policies the moment of
truth here is the payment of the claims
and even the payment of claims you have
to either be at a garage for repairing
your vehicle or if you are admitted to
hospital there is a hospital who is
processing the claim out there and also
there are third party surveyors and dpas
who aid with the process so it's a very
very physically intensive industry
of course like every other industry like
rightly mentioned the impact of the
pandemic has been that there's a
significant amount of digitization that
has happened people have moved away from
physical interactions because there was
no other way to interact at least in the
early stages of the pandemic so people
did move digital but even after moving
digital there is a lot of work that can
be done
at the same time you also see
significant shift in the kind of
products that
the consumers are demanding and as the
consumer profile is changing the gen z
coming into the population you have uh
new generation products which are
required like maybe cyber insurance
telehealth solutions even iot based risk
management solutions similarly given the
plethora of fintech and insurance out
there there are newer age products that
i mean bite size products these are the
replication of the sachet uh
fundamentals in the insurance industry
uh products covering just vector-borne
diseases or products covering just your
travel by one cab right or so and so
forth so very small ticket size products
which are emerging similarly the risks
which are emerging also
again as an industry we had to innovate
to cater for these risks pandemic of
course was one major new risk that
surfaced and we had products to cover
the pandemic plus products related to
climate change privacy and data
production and even products related to
security when you see that a lot of
organizations are promoting hybrid
working so overall the cyber security
posture needs to change so the coverages
also need to adapt to that so the entire
industry as such it has been undergoing
a significant change and the pandemic
has only accelerated that change and we
can see that we have new technologies
like ai being used for notifying claims
so when a person calls up a call center
instead of a agent taking the claim
intimation it's done through a ai uh
chatbot which guides her through the
claim intonation similarly there's a lot
of other technologies that are being
used which are really changing the
scenario and how we interact with the
customer not only during the initial
policy issuance but also at a time of
claims and how we process the claims so
girish would it be safe to say that the
changes that you personally have
experienced in this industry in say the
last two or three years have come at a
far more rapid pace than perhaps the
changes that we saw in the last decade
or so oh definitely i mean and that's
with most of the industries like the
last five years the rapid change in
technology has really given a completely
different character to many industries
and insurance is no different i mean we
have undergone significant change how we
interact with the customers has
undergone a significant change i mean
if you look at how we used to do it
earlier i mean we had
the policy issuance and
there is no actual need for a customer
to interact with the insurance provider
in case he or she doesn't have a claim
and for a health policy less than 10
percent would have claims right so at
the end of the day once you have
purchased 90 people even experience
claim the
engagement with the customer just wasn't
there so again we are trying to change
that we trying to stay engaged with the
customer through the life cycle and one
of the key things we have done in that
is our ielts care app it's a very
customer focused app and it started off
not from selling policies not from
processing claims but the focus was
engaging the customer so we have various
different social engage the customer we
have wellness solutions we have a daily
step counter we have something called a
calorie scan you want to eat that samosa
that someone gives you you can just scan
it and it'll tell you not only the
calories that you're going to consume it
also tells you how many steps you should
take or how much jimming you should do
the next day to burn off those calories
so you really are careful when
uh taking that extra samosa in yeah i
still like the sound of this product
because i am so desperately in need of
one something that tells me
you can actually pop in that samosa and
then go for your little you know 10
minute run but that's that's very cool
technology doing all kinds of things to
uh enable wellness i would imagine right
in fact we had something cooler we we
launched something called a face scan a
couple of months back just look at the
phone keep your camera on look at the
phone for two minutes gives you very
accurately almost
about six vitals of your blood pressure
heart rate spo to count all this on your
phone it's something which is remarkable
and
again very useful i mean you don't need
to carry a vp measuring machine that
clip that you attach to get the spo2 and
the thermometer you just stare at the
camera that's all you need to do so
that's power of technology today and
this is a very engaging right you have
this you are going to use that app more
and more check your health stats and you
can also have your friends compete with
you on how many steps you take and so on
so forth so not only that i mean during
the time of cover you also realize
teleconsultation is important right it's
been around a long time but really the
use of teleconsultation increased
manifold during covert and that's
integrated into our uh i'll take care
app i have a feature called hello doctor
the solution gives the customers uh 24 7
access to doctor through consultation
through video to resolve any of the
health issues during the pandemic we
also launched a home care service
solution for customers in collaboration
with the home service provider partners
here the doctor can prescribe a
treatment through the consultation after
diagnosing you and the home care service
also include monitoring by a medical
professional if the need arises nurses
doctors
physiotherapists can come and check the
patients at the residence all that can
be done we also launched the be fit
product which again takes care of all
these wellness requirements through the
app and covers your outpatient tree
so all this if you realize was never
covered as a part of health insurance
health insurance earlier was
just issue the policy and if you get
hospitalized make the payment you are
actually making it a continuum of care
rather than just a point of time
solution so that's the change that the
entire delivery of insurance is going
through and the ir take care app we've
had over a million downloads and very
good response from our customers they
really and some of the features like i
mentioned like calorie scan has really
got us great feedback from our customers
you know seeing as we've dwelt at length
on customer experiences i'd like to
understand what are those customer
behaviors that have necessitated these
changes that you have implemented that
have uh led you to tailor these tech
driven customer solutions to meet their
their needs i think it again comes from
what i told you earlier we measure nps
course we see how consumers are
recommending us to their friends and
we've noticed over time that really when
we drove deeper the engagement is
something missing so if you don't have a
claim then there is really no experience
so you don't have the advocacy coming in
and hence your ability to show your
service differentiation was not arising
and hence we kind of moved into this
space we thought look we need to keep
engaging with the customer that's one of
the insights that we drew from what we
heard customers telling us when we did a
nps surveys and csat surveys that was
what a message was coming was unlike a
bank now with upi you might be
transacting with your bank daily you
know you experience the bank service but
even before upi you used to transact
with the bank say three or four times a
month so you really have that connect
you understand you can experience the
bank services in various aspects but in
a in insurance it's buy it once a year
it gets renewed experience it only if
required and that too you would not want
to experience claim in the headquarters
so it's not something that is not so the
engagement or the bonding with your
insurance company is really not
something which is natural so we need to
create opportunities to engage and we
need to create that whole wow factor in
the customer apart from the claim
process the claim process is some place
where you need to engage with them well
and that's the whole premise on which we
kind of built out the air take care and
like i said we built it out starting
with this engagement process we
obviously have the claim servicing also
done through our take care you can
upload all your documents your claim get
your status everything on
off late we also started selling
policies through our take care because
we have a lot of rich data of customers
using the app for various uh activity
and we can see that how the coverage is
and what is it that we can give them
additionally which meets the
requirements the primary purpose of the
app earlier started from selling a
policy
no this one came last the selling policy
came uh the first purpose was engagement
helping them with the claim process
later and then the selling of policies
now a complete app but uh it started off
with just the
addressing the engagement issue now this
is from the point of view of the
customer girish it's an overwhelming
space
you know digital insurance buyers are
sometimes overwhelmed by the sheer
choice and the information there are
articles and articles whatsapp messages
from uncles and aunts on your family
groups on you know what insurance to buy
so much in a crowded market how does one
uh you know filter out the noise and
make the right decision what advice
would you give customers when they are
shopping or looking for a solution in
this space uh great questions and this
is uh really like you said a dilemma for
customers given the
overload of information that one has
today given social media and
of course whatsapp groups and so on so
forth but i would also say that that is
uh
a great thing because earlier the only
way you could buy insurance is talk to
your agent whatever the agent is telling
you kind of purchase insurance now you
have multiple channels and also there
are independent sites where you have
ratings you have reviews there's a lot
of publications which do a whole lot of
research and rate various products and
services that companies offer so the
information is there so they would need
to go through information there's no
substitute to individual research right
i mean if you need to take a distance
you need to be aware of
stuff so there is a lot of material out
there which you can read you can
understand what are the coverages but of
course then you can obviously call up
our call center where we take you
through the various products that we
offer also use the agency channel i mean
there is your friendly neighborhood
agent and he or she would always be
there to guide you on uh the most
suitable products but insurance is a
product which requires a bit of thought
so you should make yourself aware do a
bit of primary research and all
companies including us have detailed
information on their websites so
that's something which is available and
you go through a couple of them and you
understand broadly what people are
talking about what about what is not
covered you can also go through other
sites which do some of the comparisons
some of the prominent newspapers also
have a regular update of comparing uh
various products so those are also guide
posts which you can use one of the
preferred channels which customers do
have is the agent so you can talk to
your agent as well and understand what
are the products available and if you're
sure of it uh just come to our i'll take
care app or to
our website icsalambad.com and you can
buy the policy directly out there superb
and i must thank you girish for getting
us off onto a good start over here on
the very first episode of ielts cafe
we've understood the kind of customer
behaviors and expectations that have
driven the changes that we've seen in
the insurance industry we've understood
the role of technology and how really
sort of is a force multiplier when it
comes to you know consumer experience
we've also understood some of the
thinking that's gone behind these
changes that have been implemented and
thank you so much for those pieces of
advice to our uh listeners who might be
looking at insurance how they must you
know do their own research to pick the
right one for themselves all in all i
think we are sorted for the next uh
episode which i'm hoping will deep dive
into some of the topics that you have
addressed today but thank you so much
gareesh for joining us on isle cafe
today and here's wishing you and the
team the very best going forward
[Music]
you were listening to il cafe we have
you covered
[Music]
you